{
  "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
  "name": "Hand Tools",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "It is dangerous to use chisels that have",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Hard points.",
        "Mushroomed heads.",
        "Small cutting points.",
        "Rough cutting edges."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Mushroomed heads."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "A cold chisel that has a mushroomed head can be reclaimed by",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Regrinding to the recommended included angle.",
        "Grinding to the original shaft size.",
        "Re-tempering the mushroomed head.",
        "Filing the head to a ball shape."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Grinding to the original shaft size."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "File handles should be on files because",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "They reduce the risk of injury.",
        "They protect the tang from damage.",
        "They are available in a variety of attractive colours.",
        "They protect the cutting edges on the face."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["They reduce the risk of injury."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "A split hammer handle is best repaired by",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Removing and replacing it.",
        "Binding it with nylon string.",
        "Wrapping with copper wire.",
        "Taping it with electrical tape."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Removing and replacing it."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "The safest way to use a wrench is to",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Pull on it with steady pressure.",
        "Push it away from your body.",
        "Tap on it to get it started.",
        "Put a pipe handle on it for extra leverage."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Pull on it with steady pressure."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "What is the purpose of a wedge when replacing a hammer handle?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "A wedge is used to tighten the end of the handle in the eye of the hammerhead.",
          "A wedge is used to balance the hammer.",
          "A wedge is used to provide grip to the hammer handle.",
          "A wedge is used to protect the handle from damage.",
          "A wedge is used to align the hammerhead with the handle."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["A wedge is used to tighten the end of the handle in the eye of the hammerhead."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "A combination square consists of",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "A square head.",
        "A protractor.",
        "A centre-head.",
        "All of the above."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["All of the above."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "The most versatile type of square is the",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Carpenter's square.",
        "Sliding T bevel square.",
        "Combination square.",
        "Try square."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Combination square."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "A thin rule has an advantage over a thick rule when",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Accuracy is a priority.",
        "Storage room is a problem.",
        "Rough shop conditions are experienced.",
        "Graduations are in 1/16 of an inch."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Accuracy is a priority."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "A good tool for accurately transferring measurements is a",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Tape measure.",
        "Combination square.",
        "Vernier caliper.",
        "Set of dividers."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Set of dividers."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "A flexible steel rule is an advantage when",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Measuring long distances.",
        "Laying out channel iron.",
        "Finding the centres of circles.",
        "Measuring on curved surfaces."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Measuring on curved surfaces."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "To check whether or not a surface is at true vertical, you would use a",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Torpedo level.",
        "Framing square.",
        "Protractor head.",
        "Centre head."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Torpedo level."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "What is the recommended length of a wrap-a-round for marking a straight line around a pipe?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "One complete turn around the pipe.",
        "One and one quarter turns around the pipe.",
        "Twice the pipe circumference.",
        "Twice the pipe diameter."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["One and one quarter turns around the pipe."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "The size of pliers is determined by the",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Length of the jaws.",
        "Overall length of the tool.",
        "Amount the jaws will open.",
        "Maximum diameter the tool can grip."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Overall length of the tool."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "Vise grips have an advantage over pliers when",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "The tool has to grip round material.",
        "A metric size wrench is not available.",
        "You need to maintain a constant pressure.",
        "You are working on non-ferrous material."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["You need to maintain a constant pressure."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
      "question": "C-clamps are sized according to the",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Distance the clamp opens.",
        "Overall length of the clamp.",
        "Length of the screw thread.",
        "Clamping screw diameter."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Distance the clamp opens."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "A bar clamp has an advantage when",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Thick metal is being clamped.",
          "Clamping over greater distances.",
          "Material needs to be clamped to a bar.",
          "Pressure is applied in one spot."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Clamping over greater distances."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "A 32 teeth per inch hacksaw blade is the best choice for cutting",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Hard material.",
          "Soft material.",
          "Thin material.",
          "Thick material."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Thin material."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Files are classified by the",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Job you have been asked to do.",
          "Length, shape, and cut.",
          "Size, width, and kind of material.",
          "Shape, hardness, thickness, and cut."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Length, shape, and cut."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Explain why filing is done only on the forward stroke.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "Dragging the file backwards will break the teeth from the file.",
            "Filing on the forward stroke is more efficient.",
            "Backward filing will dull the file.",
            "Forward filing creates a smoother finish.",
            "Backward filing can cause uneven wear on the file."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Dragging the file backwards will break the teeth from the file."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Compound action snips have an advantage over tinners' snips when",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "The metal is thicker than 16 gauge.",
          "14-gauge galvanized iron is being cut.",
          "Non-ferrous metals are to be cut.",
          "The cut must follow a curve."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["The cut must follow a curve."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Tinners' snips are sized according to the",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Length of cut per stroke.",
          "Maximum jaw opening.",
          "Thickness that can be cut.",
          "Overall length of the tool."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Overall length of the tool."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "The cutting edge of a cold chisel should be prepared to a _______ degree angle for softer materials and up to _______ degrees for very hard materials.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "60, 90",
            "60, 60",
            "90, 90",
            "90, 60"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["60, 90"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "List an advantage an aluminum pipe wrench has over a steel pipe wrench.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "Aluminum pipe wrenches are lighter than steel pipe wrenches.",
            "Aluminum pipe wrenches are more durable than steel pipe wrenches.",
            "Aluminum pipe wrenches provide a better grip than steel pipe wrenches.",
            "Aluminum pipe wrenches are more resistant to corrosion than steel pipe wrenches.",
            "Aluminum pipe wrenches are cheaper than steel pipe wrenches."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Aluminum pipe wrenches are lighter than steel pipe wrenches."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Explain how open end, box end and combination wrenches are rated for size.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "They are sized according to the size of nut or bolt head for which they can be used.",
            "They are sized according to the length of the wrench.",
            "They are sized according to the width of the handle.",
            "They are sized according to the material they are made from.",
            "They are sized according to the weight of the wrench."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["They are sized according to the size of nut or bolt head for which they can be used."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Explain how adjustable and pipe wrenches are rated for size.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "The overall length of the tool determines size.",
            "The width of the jaws determines size.",
            "The weight of the tool determines size.",
            "The material of the tool determines size.",
            "The size of the nut or bolt head it can accommodate determines size."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["The overall length of the tool determines size."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "How are sockets sized?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "By the total number of points.",
          "By measuring the distance across the points.",
          "By measuring the distance across the flats.",
          "By the depth of the socket."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["By measuring the distance across the flats."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "An adjustable wrench is recommended when",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "The points of the nut are rounded over.",
          "You are working with metric fasteners.",
          "A proper fitting wrench is not available.",
          "Square nuts are used instead of hex nuts."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["A proper fitting wrench is not available."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "An MJ torque wrench exerts a torque pressure of _____________ on the 5/16 nut of an MJ coupling.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "60 inch-pounds",
            "50 inch-pounds",
            "70 inch-pounds",
            "80 inch-pounds",
            "90 inch-pounds"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["60 inch-pounds"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Soil pipe cutters are designed to _____________.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "cut cast iron pipe only.",
            "cut PVC pipe.",
            "cut steel pipe.",
            "cut copper pipe.",
            "cut aluminum pipe."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": ["cut cast iron pipe only."],
          "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "Fish tapes are made of",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Copper, aluminum, or steel.",
          "Aluminum, nylon, or fibreglass.",
          "Steel, nylon, or fibreglass.",
          "Copper, nylon, or aluminum."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Steel, nylon, or fibreglass."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "topicId": "b37ff3d1-6a14-46ba-9bf7-2d4702ba7572",
        "question": "What wrench would you choose when installing a valve on a piping project?",
        "type": "checkbox_type",
        "options": [
            "hex wrench",
            "spud wrench",
            "pen-end wrench"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["hex wrench", "spud wrench", "pen-end wrench"],
        "explanation": ""
      }
  ]
}
